A Guide to the Papers of Louis I. Jaffé, 1914-1986
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Louis I. Jaffé, 1914-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9924-l
This collection consists of ca. 275 items.
Mrs. Louis I. Jaffé
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was made a gift to the Library on December 2, 1986 by Mrs. Louis I. Jaffé of Norfolk, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
These additional papers consisting of ca. 275 items, chiefly covering the period 1914-1986, include correspondence, articles, speeches, newspaper clippings and other printed material, and photographs. Much of the material was collected by Louis I. Jaffé in his capacity as editor of the Virginian-Pilot but there is also material saved by Mrs. Jaffé concerning his death and tributes to him. During the process of preparing her husband's papers for the Library, Alice R. Jaffé assembled electrostatic copies of Jaffé's speeches, articles, editorials, and other writings in a bound volume entitled "Articles and Speeches by Louis I. Jaffé, Editor, Virginian-Pilot, 1919-1950."
Among the correspondence are two letters of introduction for Jaffé from Secretary of State Cordell Hull and Virginia Governor George C. Peery and autographed letters of Bruce Bliven, Gamaliel Bradford, and Struthers Burt. Topics covered in the newspaper clippings include John Garland Pollard's gubernatorial candidacy(1929), the merger of the Virginian-Pilot and Ledger-Dispatch(1933), the death of Jaffé (1950), and various articles and editorials on a wide variety of subjects such as politics, the press, and racial problems. Photographs of the Balkans include one taken there of Archduke Francis Ferdinand during his visit to Sarajevo with his wife, Sophia, prior to their assassination on June 28, 1914.
An extensive description of the contents of this collection was prepared by Mrs. Louis I. Jaffé, and can be found in the control folder.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Topical
  - Anti-Lynching 1965-1978 (Box 1)
  - Articles and Speeches by Louis I. Jaffé 1926-1943 (Box 1)
  - "Articles and Speeches by Louis I. Jaffé, Editor, Norfolk Virginian-Pilot, 1919-1950" 1920-1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
    Chapters I- original file papers
  - Articles and Speeches kept by Louis I. Jaffé 1924-1926, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Sketches of Walter Lippmann 1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1928-1943 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1938-1943 (Box 1)
    re Mural Project for the Virginian-Pilot building and solicitation of Thomas Hart Benton for the job
  - Correspondence 1929 (Box 1)
    re Pulitzer Prize
  - "Days" and "Weeks" of Special Significance 1927 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor 1924-1928 (Box 1)
  - Nineteenth Century Newspapers 1851, 1866, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
    Harper's Weekly(1866) and New York Times Daily(1851 reproduction)
  - Norfolk and Western Railway Company's application to acquire control by lease of the Virginian Railway Company 1925 (Box 1)
  - Tributes to Louis I. Jaffé 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Verses submitted to the Virginian-Pilot 1928-1935 (Box 1)
- Printed and Photographs
  - "Articles and Speeches by Louis I. Jaffé, Editor, Norfolk Virginian-Pilot, 1919-1950" 1986, Bound volume (Box 1)
  - Magazines kept by Louis I. Jaffé 1927-1949, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings and other papers 1950 (Box 2)
    re the death of Louis I. Jaffé
  - Newspaper Clippings and Reprints kept by Louis I. Jaffé 1926-1950 (Box 2)
  - Newpaper Clippings kept by Louis I. Jaffé 1921-1935 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1950-1970 (Box 2)
    re Editorial Successors to Louis I. Jaffé
  - Pamphlets and Excerpts used for Editorials 1940-1942 (Box 2)
  - Photographs of the Balkans ante 1914, 1919, n.d. (Box 2)